



Louahborouah, UK

💌 t.kelder@lboro.ac.uk | 🌴 timokelder.netlify.app | 🖸 timokelder | 🛅 timo-kelder-960867120 | 💆 @timokelder

"Large ensemble simulations to quantify and explain climate extremes"

Summary.

Timo Kelder is a PhD student in climate science at Loughborough University, with visiting status at Oxford University and ECMWF. Supervised by Professor Rob Wilby and Dr Tim Marjoribanks, he analyses big data from large-ensemble climate model simulations to improve precipitation design standards and to assess trends in extreme precipitation. As part of an MSc in Earth and Environment at Wageningen University, Timo held an internship at the Norwegian Meteorological Institute (MetNor). As hydrologist within the project 'Translating Weather Extremes into the Future' at MetNor, he was part of an integral team to tackle high-impact flood events in Norway.

Education

Loughborough University

Loughborough, UK Sep. 2018 - exp. Sep. 2021

PHD

· Large ensemble simulations to quantify and explain climate extremes.

Wageningen, The Netherlands

MSc. Earth and Environment

- Internship: Hydrological impacts of atmospheric rivers under current and future climate. Graded: 8.
- Thesis: A simplified routing model for data scarce lowland catchments. Graded: 8.
- · Courses: 8

Wageningen University and Research

Wageningen University and Research

Wageningen, The Netherlands

BSc. Soil, Water and Atmosphere

Sep. 2012 - Jul. 2015

Aug. 2015 - exp. Feb. 2018

· Thesis: Bedform height and length increase linearly with distance from the sea in a tidal environment: a pioneering study of the tidal zone of the Kapuas river. Graded: 8.

Work Experience _

The Norwegian Meteorological Institute

Oslo, Norway

• Simulating high-impact flood events in Norway as part of the TWEX project.

Feb. 2018 - Sep. 2018

Ecovision Curação

INTERN Dec. 2015 - Feb. 2016 • I applied the SWMM model to Curação to understand sediment transport in the rainwater drainage system of Curação.

Presentations

EGU 2020 Online!

PRESENTOR May 2020

Title

AGU 2018 Washington DC

PRESENTOR Dec 2018

Still need to add others

PRESENTOR

Title

TIMO KELDER · RÉSUMÉ APRIL 30, 2020